It's freezing.
Wow, did you see that, Ioryogi?
See what?
I'll do it once more!
Did you see that, did you? It's so amazing!
It's winter, I suppose.
Ah, that was a big one!
It really is winter!
How was that? Did you feel just a bit warmer?
That was mean...
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...Warmth of a Chilling Wind.
Hey, Kobato.
What is it, Ioryogi?
What comes after winter?
Spring!
That's right. There isn't much time left until spring! Do you understand?
You need to fill up this bottle with konpeito by spring.
Right...
If you don't hurry up, you'll end up not being able to go anywhere!
And when I woke up in the morning, Daddy was lying there with his tummy out!
Really? At my place, brother—
What's the matter?
That man's here again today.
Come on.
Let's go home for today, okay?
Mommy?
Hey.
I'll call the police.
I've yet to take one step into the Nursery.
You have no grounds to make a complaint.
Try harassment.
I'm just standing here.
It seems like you can't just leave kids in the nursery's care without worrying, huh.
Fujimoto?
This guy...
He's that debt collector from last time.
Let's go.
But...
Let him be.
Hello, this is Yomogi Nursery.
Oh, you're Rikako's mother?
I was worried because she wasn't here today.
Huh? Oh, that's... um...
All right.
Then I'll have to ask you to mail over the official paperwork.
Okay. Yes, that will be fine.
Then... please tell Rikako goodbye for me.
She said that Rikako will no longer be coming to the Nursey.
She's already the third child this month to quit.
Well, with this at hand,
I don't blame the parents for being worried.
Of course that's not okay!
I told you to deal with it!
What? What was that?!
Cool!
There's so much!
Thank you, Domoto.
No need for thanks.
They're all things that were lying around the house or stuff left over from the school festival.
You really helped us out though.
It looks like we'll be able to have a fun Christmas party!
I like this one! I wanna hang it up!
Miss Sayaka?
Don't push yourself too hard, okay?
I'm fine, really.
Um...
If you're looking for Fujimoto and Kobato, they're on the roof.
Right.
Miss Sayaka... looked very lonely.
She's still as kind as always...
but she looked very lonely.
Yeah.
That person...
Tell her that when the deadline comes, I'm destroying the Nursery.
You can't!
I don't care if there are still kids there.
So if you don't want anyone to get hurt, quickly get out of the way, got it?
Why does he want to do something so terrible?
Mr. Okiura is Miss Sayaka's husband, isn't he?
He has no right to be her husband.
I... I'm going to go talk to that man!
Don't!
But his presence causes trouble for everyone, doesn't it?
He's not someone you can deal with by words.
I'm sure that if I just explained
things to him, he'd understand!
I told you no, didn't I?!
Why not?
Listen up. Just stay out of this!
If another student stops coming, Miss Sayaka will be sad!
That's not something that you need to worry about.
Got it? You don't need to do anything.
But!
Domoto!
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
She's already the third child this month to quit.
Well, with this at hand,
I don't blame the parents for being worried.
I see.
Something needs to be done...
If anything could be done, I'm sure that Kiyokazu would've already done it.
I understand how you feel, but it might be better to not to do anything.
But still, I think I should go and try to talk to that man.
But...
If this continues, Yomogi Nursery will end up shutting down.
Everyone will be sad!
So I will go and try to speak with him!
Kobato!
Snow!
Let's have lots and lots of snow!
How wonderful!
Will it become all white with the snow?
Mr. Kiyokazu!
Here! Let's hang this up together?
No, no, we'll mix it together so it'll be green and white.
Cause there are also round ones around it, let's cover it with little balls, okay?
And also—!
What?
What is Dobato doing?
I'm Kobato Hanato.
Huh?
The weather's so nice today!
What?
On days like this, futons are fluffy, and it's just wonderful.
You can go and play a lot, and then come back and take a nap in your fluffy futon...
and think, tomorrow as well...
Will I be able to see everyone from Yomogi Nursery again tomorrow as well?
What the heck are you talking about?
We even went on a field trip!
We made pictures with leaves!
And potato picking was just so much fun.
And the bazaar from just a while ago - so many people came to it!
This Nursery is full of... everyone's memories...
This place is filled with memories!
So!
Please don't destroy Yomogi Nursery! I beg you!
Try saying that after you've paid back your debt.
I understand. That's why we'll pay it back, little by little!
Kobato. Even if you speak to him...
Is something the matter?
It's nothing!
And anyway, it's as the guy says. Even if you say that to me, nothing'll change.
Then... I'll speak to Mr. Okiura.
There's no way he'd listen to you!
And besides, there's no way that guy's dad would show any sympathy.
Dad?
I'm going home for today.
But I'll be back again, got it?
Please! Don't destroy—!
Goodbye!
Kobato, let's leave it at this for today.
Right...
Are you okay?
Does your stomach hurt?
Don't touch me!
But—!
Shut up... go away!
I can't!
Are you okay?!
What's the matter?!
Are you all right?!
It's...Kobato!
Takashi's there too!
He collapsed all of a sudden!
Kobato left with them.
Yeah.
Miss Sayaka?
The ambulance went bee-boo-bee-boo, didn't it?
It did.
But now, it's time to go to sleep.
Yes, this is Yomogi Nursery.
Appendicitis? I see.
Yeah, I'll tell Miss Sayaka too.
Kobato.
The surgery and everything went well.
They said things should be fine from now on.
Really?
Really. They said not to worry.
I see.
Then shall we get going?
Yes.
Oh?
What could be the matter?
That man who was standing in front of the Nursery collapsed because of appendicitis.
Appendicitis?
He's at the central hospital.
Supposedly the surgery's
completed without any problems.
Really?
Caused you some trouble, I see. Thanks.
Yeah. You're not welcome.
Then hurry up and get out of there.
There's no way you can return the money after all, right?
You get it, don't you?
Is there any chance we could talk about it?
Talk about it?
What's so funny?!
What's the matter? This isn't like you.
I'm just asking if it's possible!
No, it's not.
At any rate, thanks for letting me know.
Oh, and also—
What?
You should also give up and get out of that Nursery.
Why did I... even bother calling him...
I'm sure that if I just explained
things to him, he'd understand!
We're back.
Um... that person is fine. They said he'll get better soon.
I see.
Kobato, bye bye!
Bye bye!
Hey, Mommy, Rikako quit the Nursery.
Oh no, is that so?
Kobato, you're done for today.
But the cleaning—
Today's been a stressful day.
Hurry up home and rest up, okay?
Tomorrow's going to busy too, with the
Christmas party preparations and all. Okay?
Okay...
I'll walk you.
Domoto.
Thank you for today.
No, I really wasn't able to help much...
I'll go get my bag.
Ioryogi! I'm sorry for making you wait!
You haven't gained any new konpeito today either!
What are you gonna do about this?
But it seems like that man is going to be able to get better soon. Isn't that wonderful?
How could that be wonderful?!
Once he gets better, he's gonna come back again... Dammit!
What's the matter?
I made Fujimoto angry.
Even though he said not to do anything, I...
You haven't done anything wrong, Kobato.
There's nothing for you to worry about.
But...
Kobato.
Do you want to sit down?
What should we do?
If Yomogi Nursery closes, everyone will be sad.
What can I do to help?
Kobato.
You're always worrying about those around you, aren't you?
You're kind and honest and you always work your very hardest.
Kobato.
I like... girls like you, Kobato.
Domoto.
Thank you very much.
Thanks to you, I feel a little better.
You're welcome.
Here you go.
It's so warm.
Thank you very much.
Kobato.
Yes, what is it?
On Christmas...
Let's...
Kiyokazu.
Are you going home now?
Yeah.
Oh yeah. If there's anything else you need for the Christmas party, let me know.
All right.
Thank you for your scarf.
Then, I'll see you later.
Bye.
See you.
Yeah.
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...White Christmas.